<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on Stephen Finucane (Fin-oo-can)</title>
    <link>https://that.guru/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on Stephen Finucane (Fin-oo-can)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-IE</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://that.guru/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trading Flexibility for Performance: The HPC Story in OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/trading-flexibility-for-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/trading-flexibility-for-performance/</guid>
      <description>This lightning talk was presented at OpenStack Days CERN in May 2019. It gave an overview of the state of the art for HPC and NFV in the OpenStack Compute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Documentation, The Openstack Way</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/working-with-documentation-the-openstack-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/working-with-documentation-the-openstack-way/</guid>
      <description>This talk was co-presented with Alex Settle at the Denver OpenStack Summit in April 2019. It serves as a brief history of documentation within OpenStack along with a how-to on contributing to documentation today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Somebody *Please* Tell Me What Is Going On?</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/will-someone-please-tell-me-whats-going-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/will-someone-please-tell-me-whats-going-on/</guid>
      <description>This was a talk I gave at the inaugural PyCon Limerick in March 2019. I explored some tools available within the Python ecosystem that can be used to manage change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Needs pandoc When You Have Sphinx?</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/who-needs-pandoc-when-you-have-sphinx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/who-needs-pandoc-when-you-have-sphinx/</guid>
      <description>This was a talk I gave at FOSDEM 2019. In this talk, subtitled &amp;ldquo;An exploration of the parsers and builders of the Sphinx documentation tool&amp;rdquo;, I explored some of the less well known aspects of both Sphinx and docutils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Double* the Performance of vSwitch-based Deployments</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/how-to-double-the-performance-of-vswitch-based-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/how-to-double-the-performance-of-vswitch-based-deployments/</guid>
      <description>This was a talk I have at the OpenStack Summit Berlin in November 2018. In this talk, I discussed the NUMA-aware vSwitches feature recently added to OpenStack Nova, explaining what it was, why you&amp;rsquo;d want it and how you could use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wonders of NUMA</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/the-wonders-of-numa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/the-wonders-of-numa/</guid>
      <description>This talk was presented at the OpenStack Summit in Vancouver in May 2018. It provided an in-depth summary of what NUMA is and why it matters so much for high-performance workloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Lion, A Head, and A Dash of YAML</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/a-lion-a-head-and-a-dash-of-yaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/a-lion-a-head-and-a-dash-of-yaml/</guid>
      <description>This talk, delivered at FOSDEM 2018, provided a quick dive into the somewhat complicated world of Sphinx extensions. Sphinx is an incredibly powerful tool but, surprisingly for a documentation, suffers from poor quality documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping It Real(Time)</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/keeping-it-real-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/keeping-it-real-time/</guid>
      <description>This talk was an expanded version of the talk I had given previously at the Sydney OpenStack Summit and, as then, I once again discussed the real-time capabilities of OpenStack Nova.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping It Real(Time)</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/keeping-it-real-time-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/keeping-it-real-time-sydney/</guid>
      <description>Update: An expanded version of this talk was delivered at FOSDEM 2018 and is well worth the read if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in this.
This talk was given as a lightning talk at the OpenStack Summit in Sydney in November 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailing List, Meet CI</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/mailing-list-meet-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/mailing-list-meet-ci/</guid>
      <description>This talk was presented as a lightning talk at FOSDEM 2017. It described the CI features provided in Patchwork 2.0, which was at the time unreleased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Patchwork</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/a-new-patchwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/a-new-patchwork/</guid>
      <description>This was my first ever presentation to an audience that wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely my colleagues or fellow students. It was delivered as a lightning talk at FOSDEM 2016 and focused on the work that had been done to bring Patchwork up-to-date, after it had languished for a couple of years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>