<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Stephen Finucane (Fin-oo-can)</title>
    <link>https://that.guru/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Stephen Finucane (Fin-oo-can)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-IE</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://that.guru/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct vs Hostdev Interfaces in nova</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/direct-vs-hostdev-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/direct-vs-hostdev-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>Mostly a note for myself. There are two types of SR-IOV&amp;rsquo;y networks supported in nova: direct and hostdev. Confusingly, the latter corresponds to passthrough of the virtual function (VF), while the former corresponds to macvtap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poon Hill Trek</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/poon-hill-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/poon-hill-trek/</guid>
      <description>So, there I was, in Nepal for two weeks with a friend, wanting to try some of the world-renowned trekking along with exploring the cities of Kathmandu and Pokhara.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Mellanox ConnectX-3 NIC firmware</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/updating-mellanox-connectx-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/updating-mellanox-connectx-3/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I provided a guide on configuring SR-IOV for a Mellanox ConnectX-3 NIC. I&amp;rsquo;ve since picked up a second one of these and was attempting to follow through on the same guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring SR-IOV for a Mellanox ConnectX-3 NIC</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/sriov-mellanox-connectx-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/sriov-mellanox-connectx-3/</guid>
      <description>So SR-IOV support in my Intel I350-T2V2 decided to stop working recently (or maybe it never worked - I can&amp;rsquo;t be sure), meaning it was time to pick up a new SR-IOV NIC for testing/development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Set The Name of tmux Windows</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/automatically-set-tmux-window-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/automatically-set-tmux-window-name/</guid>
      <description>I recently updated to Fedora 28 which includes a updated version of tmux - tmux 2.7. I quickly noted that my window title was no longer being set as before and eventually identified the issue: a breaking change in 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution Calendar Issues</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/evolution-calendar-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/evolution-calendar-issues/</guid>
      <description>I started Evolution this morning and noticed half of my calendar events were missing. Attempts to refresh said calendar resulted in the following errors message:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building PDFs for OpenStack documentation</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/create-pdfs-for-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/create-pdfs-for-openstack/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve only ever really worked with HTML and man page builds for the documentation various of various OpenStack projects. However, OpenStack uses Sphinx across the board and Sphinx, being the awesome tool that it is, supports many other output formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Real Time Openstack</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/deploying-real-time-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/deploying-real-time-openstack/</guid>
      <description>Recent versions of OpenStack nova have added support for real-time instances, that is, instances that provide the determinism and performance guarantees required by real-time applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patchwork and CI in a tree</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/patchwork-and-ci-in-a-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/patchwork-and-ci-in-a-tree/</guid>
      <description>This has been a long time in the works.
With the upcoming release of Patchwork 2.0, Patchwork will provides first class support for series, or collections of patches, and expose these (and much more besides) over a new REST API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Python paths with vim</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/open-python-paths-with-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/open-python-paths-with-vim/</guid>
      <description>In OpenStack nova land, you run tests by specifying their Python paths, like so:
$ tox -e py27 nova.tests.unit.virt.libvirt.test_vif.LibvirtVifTestCase  This is also how tests are run and reported by the CI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Windows 7 USB on Fedora 25</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/creating-a-windows-7-usb-on-fedora-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/creating-a-windows-7-usb-on-fedora-25/</guid>
      <description>Turns out Fedora 25 didn&amp;rsquo;t like my Samsung Series 9 (NP900X4C) much. Among other things, the WiFi was intermittent (weird, as it&amp;rsquo;s an Intel NIC), suspend didn&amp;rsquo;t work (the laptop is always dead when I come to it), and the keyboard backlight turned off immediately after turning it on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Netbeans on Fedora 25</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/install-netbeans-on-fedora-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/install-netbeans-on-fedora-25/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last wrote a non-trivial amount of Java and I can&amp;rsquo;t say I miss it. However, I want to work on a plugin for Jenkins which means diving back in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTUs in neutron</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/mtus-in-neutron/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/mtus-in-neutron/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not overly familiar with neutron but it appears that in the past correctly setting MTU values was easier said than done. This has been massively improved in recent releases, but getting us to this point required a lot of work and, in particular, a lot of changes to the MTU-related configuration options available over the course of Liberty and Newton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using git-review</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/how-to-use-git-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/how-to-use-git-review/</guid>
      <description>git-review is a Python wrapper for many of the common Git commands used in conjunction with Gerrit. It encapsulates many of the most common commands used, in order to speed things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU Autotest</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/gnu-autotest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/gnu-autotest/</guid>
      <description>GNU Autotest is a test framework that, together with supporting scripts and unit test files, can unit test an application. Autotest is part of the Autotools library, a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How are datacenters physically wired?</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/how-are-datacenters-physically-wired/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/how-are-datacenters-physically-wired/</guid>
      <description>I sent this question to my team in Intel some time ago.
 I gave a run down on SDN, NFV and all things Open to the OpenStack new hires today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading mailing list archives with Mutt</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/mutt-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/mutt-archives/</guid>
      <description>You can use Mutt to load archives from a mailing list. This is useful for replying to mails when you weren&amp;rsquo;t previously subscribed to said mailing list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Jenkins &#43; Chrome</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/helpful-jenkins-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/helpful-jenkins-plugins/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I had to work with Jenkins directly (since I started on OpenStack, really). However, I had a few tricks picked up around plugins for Chrome that make working with pre-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sane Outlook: Making plain text better in Outlook</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/sane-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/sane-outlook/</guid>
      <description>I like well-formatted, plain text emails, and I like reading them in a monospace font. I find plain text to be more readable, and provides less ways for people to impact this legibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Work</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/how-i-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/how-i-work/</guid>
      <description>Next Friday is the last week of this stint at Intel, so I figured now was as good a time as ever to do a write up on how I work, or, more accurately, how I&amp;rsquo;ve worked, during my time here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resizing pinned instances to unpinned</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/resizing-pinned-to-unpinned/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/resizing-pinned-to-unpinned/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack Nova provides support for resize operations, or the changing of the flavor associated with instance. This allows you to add or remove resources from the instance, in addition to modifying other configuration associated with the flavor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPU pinning with image metadata</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/cpu-pinning-with-image-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/cpu-pinning-with-image-metadata/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack Nova allows the specification of image metadata to provide per-instance metadata. This is similar to the flavor extra specs. The CPU pinning feature makes use of this to allow for configuration of CPU policies and CPU thread policies via such metdata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring ZNC with HexChat</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/znc-sasl-server-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/znc-sasl-server-pass/</guid>
      <description>Configuring ZNC with HexChat I recently set up ZNC instance to capture whatever I may miss when not connected to any of the many OpenStack IRC channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This is my new, Hugo-powered blog. I have a backlog of articles to publish, so expect to see lots of material going up here in the next few weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>