<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Stephen Finucane (Fin-oo-can)</title>
    <link>https://that.guru/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Stephen Finucane (Fin-oo-can)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-IE</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://that.guru/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Poon Hill Trek</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/poon-hill-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/poon-hill-trek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, there I was, in Nepal for two weeks with a friend, wanting to try some of
the world-renowned trekking along with exploring the cities of Kathmandu and
Pokhara.  I only had two weeks, which unfortunately ruled out both the famous
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikivoyage.org/wiki/Everest_Base_Camp_Trek&#34;&gt;Everest Base Camp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikivoyage.org/wiki/Annapurna_Circuit&#34;&gt;Annapurna Circuit&lt;/a&gt; treks, along with treks through
the less well known but apparently stunning &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikivoyage.org/wiki/Langtang_Valley_Trek&#34;&gt;Langtang Valley&lt;/a&gt;, given that all
take a minimum of nine days to complete. That left, according to the wisdom of
the internet, a trek to Poon Hill (Ghorepani) in the Annapurna Valley as my
best option and this is roughly what we did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are my rough notes from that trek, which took place in November 2018.
With any luck, I&amp;rsquo;ll get most of this published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikivoyage.org/&#34;&gt;Wikivoyage&lt;/a&gt; before long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-there&#34;&gt;Getting there&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d flown into and was staying in Kathmandu, the capital, but pretty much all
treks in the Annapurna region start from Pokhara, the second biggest city in
Nepal. As such, our first step was to get from Kathmandu to Pokhara. How to do
this is pretty well documented but, in summary, you can either fly or take a
tourist bus. Flying is much faster (30 minutes vs. 6-7 hours) but significantly
more expensive (~120 USD vs. 500-800 NPR) so we ended up taking the bus. This
itself was an interesting experience, given that seemed to spend as much time
driving alongside the road, which was closed for resurfacing, as we did on the
road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Pokhara, you need to get to Nayapul. You can take either a bus from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lonelyplanet.com/nepal/pokhara/transport/getting-there-away/land&#34;&gt;Baglung bus station&lt;/a&gt; or do what we did and get a taxi. Buses apparently cost
~200 Rs. per person while a taxi will be ~2000 Rs. total. Once you arrive in
Nayapul, you can start walking towards Birethanti, where the various park
checkpoints are located.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;itinerary&#34;&gt;Itinerary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started from Pokhara rather late (~11am) and arrived in Neyapul, near
Neyapul Trekking Starting Point, around 1pm. From here, we walked down to
Birethanti where we passed two checkpoints: first for the TIMS, the trekking
permit (2000 Rs. if purchased in Pohkara, same onsite), and the second for the
conservation area pass (3000 Rs. if purchased in Pokhara, 6000 Rs. if purchased
onsite). From here, you can choose to do the loop two ways. We went to
Ghorepani, which is the easier, nicer route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://that.guru/media/poon_hill_day_1_a.jpg&#34;
    alt=&#34;The taxi ride to Nayapul was&amp;hellip;interesting.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The taxi ride to Nayapul was&amp;hellip;interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at Ulleri, which was just below our targeted destination of
Banthanti, as it was starting to get dark by 5pm (sundown around 5:30pm). As
there were there just two of us, we were able to get a room (with attached hot
shower!) for free once we bought food. Total came to 3400 Rs. which included
dinner and breakfast - both with beverages - along with a bottle of water in
the morning. This is the only place we stayed at that included a hot shower in
the room and we were certainly glad to have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://that.guru/media/poon_hill_day_1_b.jpg&#34;
    alt=&#34;We finally made it to Ulleri.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;We finally made it to Ulleri.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://that.guru/media/poon_hill_day_1_c.jpg&#34;
    alt=&#34;Warm bed? Check. Hot shower? Check.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Warm bed? Check. Hot shower? Check.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;day-2&#34;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rose after sunrise and left about 8:30am. Arrived in Ghorepani about 11:30am
and got ourselves some coffee and baked goods before heading onto Poon Hill
(side note: the machine in the coffee shop here apparently weighs 70+ kg and
was carried up on someone&amp;rsquo;s back. As you do). If we had been able to make it
here the day before (ambitious though doable), we could have headed up to Poon
Hill for sunrise (expect at 4:30am rise as it&amp;rsquo;s a 45min - 1 hour climb - you
have to pay an entry fee at this time too), which is supposed to be amazing. We
didn&amp;rsquo;t fancy hanging around Ghorepani until the next day so we went up straight
after our coffee. Even at this time, the view is still outstanding and we hung
around here for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://that.guru/media/poon_hill_day_2_a.jpg&#34;
    alt=&#34;The sort of famous Poon Hill sign.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The sort of famous Poon Hill sign.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://that.guru/media/poon_hill_day_2_b.jpg&#34;
    alt=&#34;The view from the top.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The view from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were done, we headed back down to Ghorepani, leaving here at 2:30pm,
arriving in Deurali at 3:40pm, followed by Ban Thanti at 4:30pm, and finished
up in Tadapani at 5:40pm. This was a bit late, given that it was essentially
dark by then, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything too challenging physically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided we&amp;rsquo;d leave Tadapani a little earlier than we&amp;rsquo;d left Ulleri the day
before and headed off at 8:10am. Got to Ghandruk about 10:10, where we grabbed
some tea here before heading onto Jhinu Danda and the nearby Jhinu hot springs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This initially wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad, as we simply doubled back in ourselves and
walked towards a place called Little Paradise. From Little Paradise though, we
got totally lost. We were told to &amp;ldquo;follow the electricity lines&amp;rdquo; and the blue
and white markers along the trail. We did the former and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before
we realized we were totally lost and ended up walking through farms and &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo;
tracks. Google Maps was all but useless in the area so we very much relied on
the map we&amp;rsquo;d brought with us. We were very happy to see the suspension bridge
before Jhinu Danda and ended up arriving about 3:30pm, having expected to
arrive about 2pm. We had a quick lunch in Jhinu Danda before heading down to
the hot springs for a soak. After this, we went back to Jhinu Danda where we
stayed for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://that.guru/media/poon_hill_day_3_a.jpg&#34;
    alt=&#34;One of the many steel &amp;ldquo;rope bridges&amp;rdquo; we crossed on our way. Most of these were provided by the Gurkhas.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;One of the many steel &amp;ldquo;rope bridges&amp;rdquo; we crossed on our way. Most of these were provided by the Gurkhas.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://that.guru/media/poon_hill_day_3_b.jpg&#34;
    alt=&#34;The walk down to the hot springs.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The walk down to the hot springs.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;day-4&#34;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d planned to make our way back Birethanti along the west side of the river,
instead of crossing the &amp;ldquo;New Bridge&amp;rdquo; and travelling via Landruk. This turned
out to be a terrible idea. We&amp;rsquo;re still not sure what we did wrong but we got
totally lost on the way and ended up walking through fields. We were fortuitous
enough to meet a local farmer passing through one of this fields, who put us on
the right path (which happened to also take us via his family&amp;rsquo;s restaurant,
heh). From here, it was a long, rather dull walk down into the valley, where we
were able to get a taxi straight back to Pokhara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://that.guru/media/poon_hill_day_4.jpg&#34;
    alt=&#34;Day 4 was mostly spent walking by (and through) farms like this one.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Day 4 was mostly spent walking by (and through) farms like this one.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-notes&#34;&gt;Additional Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;agencies-vs-guides-vs-solo-travel&#34;&gt;Agencies vs. guides vs. solo travel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three ways to organize a trek in Nepal. Firstly, you can use an
agency. These can be booked online or in Kathmandu or Pokhara as soon as you
arrive. They will organize everything for you, including guides, porters, food
and accommodation but they are by far the most expensive option, particularly
when booked online. Unless you&amp;rsquo;ve a good reason not to, you&amp;rsquo;re almost always
going to be better off organizing a guide yourself or, if possible (some areas
require a guide or may be considered too challenging to do solo), by travelling
solo (as in, just you and your friends). Given that the Poon Hill trek is a
relatively easy, short trek, we opted for the latter and the below guide is
based on this. If you do want a guide though, I can&amp;rsquo;t stress enough &lt;em&gt;(a)&lt;/em&gt; the
importance of meeting your guide before you travel (you&amp;rsquo;re going to be spending
days with this person - make sure you like each other) and &lt;em&gt;(b)&lt;/em&gt; the value of
shopping around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;permits&#34;&gt;Permits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To trek in the Annapurna Conservation Area, you require both a &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.welcomenepal.com/plan-your-trip/tims-card.html&#34;&gt;Trekkers&#39;
Information Management Systems&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (TIMS) card and a conservation area pass.
These cost 2000 Rs. and 3000 Rs. respectively. Both of these should be
purchased in Pokhara or Kathmandu before you travel. If you forget (or didn&amp;rsquo;t
know, as was the issue for us), these can be purchased at the checkpoints to
the park in Birethanti but for a higher price (2000 Rs. for the TIMS card but
6000 Rs. for the conservation area pass).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-drink-and-accommodation&#34;&gt;Food, drink and accommodation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up spending roughly 3500-4000 Rs. a day between two of us and in all
but one village, we were able to negotiate free accommodation in exchange for
purchasing two meals. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the case for everyone and I suspect it very
much depends on whether you&amp;rsquo;re travelling solo or not, the time of year, and
how busy the particular tea house you wish to stay in is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-to-visit&#34;&gt;When to visit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visited in November, which marks the end of peak tourist season. The weather
was decent, raining only once during our time there, and it&amp;rsquo;s a lot warmer than
December, when it can be -7°C during day, dropping to as low as -20°C during
the night. We were told it&amp;rsquo;s visiting in March or April can also be a good idea
as the forest is in full bloom. Note that it&amp;rsquo;s a lot warmer at this time of
year, however.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
