<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openstack on Stephen Finucane (Fin-oo-can)</title>
    <link>https://that.guru/categories/openstack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openstack on Stephen Finucane (Fin-oo-can)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-IE</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://that.guru/categories/openstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NUMA, CPU Pinning and &#39;vcpu_pin_set&#39;</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/cpu-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/cpu-resources/</guid>
      <description>The libvirt driver in the OpenStack Compute service (nova) has supported instance NUMA topologies for a number of releases. A NUMA topology can be added to an instance either explicitly, using the hw:numa_nodes=N flavor extra spec, or implicitly, by requesting a specific mempage size (hw:mem_page_size=N) or CPU pinning (hw:cpu_policy=dedicated).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Mellanox ConnectX-3 NIC Firmware</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/updating-mellanox-connectx-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/updating-mellanox-connectx-3/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I provided a guide on configuring SR-IOV for a Mellanox ConnectX-3 NIC. I&amp;rsquo;ve since picked up a second one of these and was attempting to follow through on the same guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Double* the Performance of vSwitch-based Deployments</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/how-to-double-the-performance-of-vswitch-based-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/how-to-double-the-performance-of-vswitch-based-deployments/</guid>
      <description>This was a talk I have at the OpenStack Summit Berlin in November 2018. In this talk, I discussed the NUMA-aware vSwitches feature recently added to OpenStack Nova, explaining what it was, why you&amp;rsquo;d want it and how you could use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring SR-IOV for a Mellanox ConnectX-3 NIC</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/sriov-mellanox-connectx-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/sriov-mellanox-connectx-3/</guid>
      <description>So SR-IOV support in my Intel I350-T2V2 decided to stop working recently (or maybe it never worked - I can&amp;rsquo;t be sure), meaning it was time to pick up a new SR-IOV NIC for testing/development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wonders of NUMA</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/the-wonders-of-numa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/the-wonders-of-numa/</guid>
      <description>This talk was presented at the OpenStack Summit in Vancouver in May 2018. It provided an in-depth summary of what NUMA is and why it matters so much for high-performance workloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping It Real(Time)</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/keeping-it-real-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/keeping-it-real-time/</guid>
      <description>This talk was an expanded version of the talk I had given previously at the Sydney OpenStack Summit and, as then, I once again discussed the real-time capabilities of OpenStack Nova.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building PDFs for OpenStack documentation</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/create-pdfs-for-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/create-pdfs-for-openstack/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve only ever really worked with HTML and man page builds for the documentation various of various OpenStack projects. However, OpenStack uses Sphinx across the board and Sphinx, being the awesome tool that it is, supports many other output formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping It Real(Time)</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/talks/keeping-it-real-time-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/talks/keeping-it-real-time-sydney/</guid>
      <description>Update: An expanded version of this talk was delivered at FOSDEM 2018 and is well worth the read if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in this.
This talk was given as a lightning talk at the OpenStack Summit in Sydney in November 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Real Time Openstack</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/deploying-real-time-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/deploying-real-time-openstack/</guid>
      <description>Recent versions of OpenStack nova have added support for real-time instances, that is, instances that provide the determinism and performance guarantees required by real-time applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Python Paths with vim</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/open-python-paths-with-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/open-python-paths-with-vim/</guid>
      <description>In OpenStack nova land, you run tests by specifying their Python paths, like so:
$ tox -e py27 nova.tests.unit.virt.libvirt.test_vif.LibvirtVifTestCase  This is also how tests are run and reported by the CI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTUs in Neutron</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/mtus-in-neutron/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/mtus-in-neutron/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not overly familiar with neutron but it appears that in the past correctly setting MTU values was easier said than done. This has been massively improved in recent releases, but getting us to this point required a lot of work and, in particular, a lot of changes to the MTU-related configuration options available over the course of Liberty and Newton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using git-review</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/how-to-use-git-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/how-to-use-git-review/</guid>
      <description>git-review is a Python wrapper for many of the common Git commands used in conjunction with Gerrit. It encapsulates many of the most common commands used, in order to speed things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resizing Pinned Instances to Unpinned</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/resizing-pinned-to-unpinned/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/resizing-pinned-to-unpinned/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack Nova provides support for resize operations, or the changing of the flavor associated with instance. This allows you to add or remove resources from the instance, in addition to modifying other configuration associated with the flavor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPU Pinning with Image Metadata</title>
      <link>https://that.guru/blog/cpu-pinning-with-image-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://that.guru/blog/cpu-pinning-with-image-metadata/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack Nova allows the specification of image metadata to provide per-instance metadata. This is similar to the flavor extra specs. The CPU pinning feature makes use of this to allow for configuration of CPU policies and CPU thread policies via such metdata.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>